Kiran Mani

Consultant Engineer (Medical Implants) - HCL America

West Chester, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Kiran-Mani/c153065bc6d84406

14+ years of Domain and Project Management experience of Aerospace, Medical Implants, Automobile, Semiconductor & Solar Equipment's involving Product life cycle management and Engineering Change Management and using CAD packages Pro/Engineer, Pro/Intralink, Wind-chill, AutoCAD, Unigraphics, Team centre, Solid works & Inventor for design solutions. Having Good skills of Team Leading and developing of offshore/Onsite teams for end to end Engineering solutions.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant Engineer (Medical Implants)

HCL America - January 2014 to Present

Nature of Job: Product Design Support, Design Modifications, New Design Releases through Engineering Change Management process and Interaction with Suppliers for Engineering queries and reviews. Product Life Cycle Management, Obsolescence management, Project Co-ordination, Project Tracking, Weekly and Monthly Report and metrics generation, attending review and weekly meetings with clients. Onsite-Offshore coordination.

Systems Engineer, Technical Lead

Xerox, Axcelis - August 2010 to January 2014

Nature of Job: Product Design Support, Design Modifications, New Design Releases through Engineering Change Management process and Interaction with Suppliers for Engineering queries and reviews. Prototype Testing and reporting, Manufacturing Support, Product Design Reviews, Product Life Cycle Management, Obsolescence management, Project Co-ordination, Project Tracking, Weekly and Monthly Report and metrics generation, attending review and weekly meetings with clients. Onsite-Offshore coordination.

Senior Engineer

Mahindra Satyam - May 2006 to July 2010

Client: Applied Materials Domain: Semiconductors

- Engineering Change Order Creation and follow-up for its closure
- Resolving Supplier Problem Sheet (SPS)
- Production & Prototype Design Support Activity
- Standard Operating Procedure Creation and Modification

Member Technical Staff

HCL Technologies LTD - February 2004 to May 2006

Client: Axelis & Novellus Domain: Semiconductors

- Obsolescence Management of mechanical and electrical parts
- BOM check and Creation of spec sheets for commercial parts
- Commercial parts Library Management & Large Assembly Management
- Develop new vendor for purchasing for low cost products.

Design Engineer

Harita Infoserve Ltd - February 2003 to February 2004

Client: Ingersoll-Rand Domain: Automobile

- Reverse Engineering the consumer product using Pro-E.
- Creating 3D CAD Model and assembly of components used Mining Equipment's.
- Maintained close liaison with engineering personnel involved in project, effectively making design modifications as required

Pro-E Designer

Mechatronics Ltd - April 2002 to February 2003

Client: TVS Motors Domain: Automobile

- Designing of Press tools, Jigs & Fixture, Gauges, Pipe Bending Tools for Automobile Parts
- · Coordinating with Production and quality for assembly related problems
- Tool Try-outs & Trouble shooting assembly related problems. Quality checking of components

Application Engineer

Incite Cam Centre - July 2001 to April 2002

Client: TVS Motors, BHELMICO Domain: Automobile

- Reverse Engineering and Model Construction
- Manufacturing Cost & Assembly Time Analysis and Design Recommendations
- Training new and existing team members

EDUCATION

M.S.

Ramaiah School of Advanced Studies - Bangalore, Karnataka September 2007

Diploma in Tool and die making in Press Tool, Molds

Government tool room and training center - Bangalore, Karnataka 1996 to 2001

SKILLS

Engineering Change Order (10+ years), Creo (2 years), Pro-E (10+ years), Unigraphics (5 years), Solid Works (2 years), Project management (5 years), Engineering change Notice (10+ years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kirankumar-mani/b/4a2/1b0

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Involved in Product design Support, Reverse Engineering, Detail Design, Quality & cost control of different types of Semi-Conductor Products, Automobile Products and Multifunctional Printers.
- · Sound knowledge on conventional and Non-Conventional machining processes.
- Basic Knowledge on Press Tools, Plastic Molds, Jigs and Fixture.
- Basic Knowledge on GD&T.

- Basic Knowledge on Value Engineering and DFMA.
- Excellent ability to read all engineering drawings.
- Sound knowledge of CAD/PLM/PDM Software like Pro-E, Intralink, Uni-Graphics, Team Centre, Solid Works, Auto CAD, SAP, Oracle and Windchill.
- Sound knowledge of Engineering Change Order and Product Life cycle.
- Efficiently manage ECO / PDM process for manufacturing sites across the globe
- · Work closely with Engineering and materials teams to review product updates / modifications
- Mentor the team and guide them towards effective discharge of functions.
- Training new and existing team members
- Maintain excellent relationship with internal customers at site and with key stakeholders in the organization
- · Identify, recommend, and implement operational efficiencies to drive continuous improvement